<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    
    <category>
        <pattern>HI</pattern>
        <template>Hello, I am your virtual assistant.  If you would like for me 
        to assist you, simply type "begin"
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>begin</pattern>
        <template>Awesome, before we get started, what is your name?</template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>My name is *</pattern>
        <that>Awesome, before we get started, what is your name</that>
        <template>
            Hello <set name = "username"> <star/></set>
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>awesome, before we get started, what is your name</that>
        <template>
            Hello <set name = "username"> <star/></set>. I am designed to help
            Computer Science majors to explore career paths.  Are you a CS major?
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>yes</pattern>
        <that>Are you a CS major</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name = "topic">CS</set></think>
            Alright, lets narrow the field down a bit.  Are you artistic or
            enjoy HTML,CSS, or JavaSCript over other programming languages?
            
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>no</pattern>
        <that>Are you a CS major</that>
        <template>
            I am currently not set up to help you with your major, have a great day!
        </template>
        
    </category>
    
        
    <topic name = "cs">
        
        <category>
            <pattern>yes</pattern>
            <that>Are you artistic or
            enjoy HTML,CSS, or JavaSCript over other programming languages</that>
            <template>
                I think Front-end web development is a great fit for you! According to wikipedia
                web-developers can expect to make around 65,000 a year, with a 
                projected job growth of 27% over the next ten years! check it out, https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_developer
            </template>
        </category>>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>no</pattern>
            <that>Are you artistic or
            enjoy HTML,CSS, or JavaSCript over other programming languages</that>
            <template>
                Sounds like web-development is not for you!  How about SQL? There
                are many opportunies centered around databases.  Tell me which
                of the following areas interest you.
                <br></br>
                <br></br>
                1. Big data and using langauges such as python to analyze data 
                trends.
                <br></br>
                2. Designing databases
                <br></br>
                3. Neither are particularly interesting to me, show me other career
                paths!
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name = "choice"><star/></set></think>
                <condition name = "choice" value = "1"> I would recommend you look
                into data analyst as a career option.  Data analyst can expect 
                and median salary of 86,000, growth is expected to increase
                by 25% over the next 10 yeras, according 
                to https://www.discoverdatascience.org/career-information/data-analyst/#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20BLS%2C%20employment,the%20average%20for%20all%20occupations.
                </condition>
                <condition name = "choice" value = "2"> I would recommend you look into
                a career as a database engineer.  The median salary is about 82,000 
                and expected growth is 11% over the next ten years according to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_administrator
                <br></br>
                </condition>
                <condition name = "choice" value = "3"> That's alright!
                Lets explore some more options.
                <br></br>
                <br></br>
                A. I enjoy desinging programs, debugging, and desinging test.
                <br></br>
                B. I don't like any of the options offered so far!
                What are my options?
                
                </condition>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <that>What are my options</that>
            <template>
                <think><set name = "choice"><star/></set></think>
                <condition name = "choice" value = "a"> I would recommend a career
                as a software developer.  The median salary is 100,000 and is
                growing at 17% over the next 10 years according to: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programmer 
                </condition>
                <condition name = "choice" value = "b"> It looks like a traditional
                coding job is not for you but thats okay!  I would have you look into
                a project management career.  Often times project managers need
                to have a baseline understanding of operating systems, psuedocode
                 and logic.  A degree is CS with some certifcations should open some
                 doors for you. You should  head over to https://www.pmi.org for more information </condition>
                
            </template>
        </category>
        
        
        
    </topic>
    



</aiml>
